ABDUL-MATIN ADEBAYO

Phone: +44 7867436755 | Email: madeayo04@gmail.com | United Kingdom

Github: https://github.com/abdul-matin0 Website: https://abdulmatin.netlify.app

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdul-matin-adebayo/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-oriented .NET Software Developer with experience designing and implementing scalable, secure solutions and web application development for complex systems across diverse industries. Possess working knowledge in web services technologies, microservice architecture, and development of Service-Oriented Applications (SOA) based on Rest APIs using Microsoft .NET Framework.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Microsoft.NET
- Blazor
- C#
- Microservices
- WPF (Windows
 Presentation Foundate
 - Presentation Foundation)

- Messaging Platforms
- JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, AngularJS, Vue.js
- SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MongoDB
- Virtual Reality and Game Development with Unity

- Docker, Kubernetes
- Cloud Services
- DevOps. Microsoft Azure, AWS
- Quality Assurance
- Unit Testing
- Project Management

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Highly adaptable with interpersonal, leadership, teamwork, time management, and communication skills.
- Successfully leads and manages projects through coordination, thinking strategically and analytically with clear direction.
- Familiarity with cloud technologies, technical and architectural design and development, and user stories requirement analysis.
- Knowledge of core software packages and tools, including RESTful APIs, SOAP Web Services, and Entity Framework.
- Experience with dependency injection containers, Object Oriented Design, Test Driven Development (TDD), and developing applications within an Azure environment.
- Proficient in application design, development, and implementation, with a focus on producing high-quality code through rigorous unit testing and debugging techniques.

CAREER ACHIEVEMENT

- Played a key role in executing a transformation from heavy, monolithic backend applications to a scalable and efficient Microservices architecture, resulting in enhanced agility and scalability of the application.
- Led the successful development and maintenance of an innovative Property Management Solution powered by Artificial Intelligence, revolutionizing the way property services are managed.
- Successfully led a team of software engineers in delivering a timely and impactful upgrade to the company's existing application.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

.NET Software Developer - Novacept - London, UK

Nov 2022 - Present

- Built and maintained a cutting-edge Property Management Solution (Powered by Artificial Intelligence) using Blazor and API
 technologies during a contract term. The solution offers homeowners and tenants an intuitive online software platform for managing
 property services, including tenant information management, payment processing, generation of financial reports, and more.
- Designed and developed a comprehensive talent life cycle platform, encompassing the entire Hire-to-Retire process. This platform efficiently manages candidates, partners, clients, hiring managers, account managers, and recruiters. Through worldwide sourcing capabilities and optimized resource allocation, this solution empowers organizations in effective talent management.
- Engaged in comprehensive system study and proficient in database engineering tasks, including the creation of databases, tables, intricate stored procedures, and SQL Performance Tuning. These efforts have significantly improved data manipulation capabilities and ensured enhanced consistency.

.NET Software Developer - Triversa Solutions Limited

Feb 2021 - Nov 2022

- Led a team of engineers in developing a financial and Anti-Money Laundering (AML) reporting enterprise application for government cooperations and banking institutions.
- Designed and developed a regulatory software (Failed bank management system) for regulatory bodies to manage failed banks.
- Responsible for designing and developing an ETL process to efficiently handle a large volume of customer data.
- Optimized performance and scalability of intricate SQL stored procedures through thorough tuning efforts. Implemented asynchronous call functions to enhance application performance, allowing for improved responsiveness and scalability.
- Stress-tested server code to validate code changes and supported multiple test phases with test data set up.

Backend Developer - SAED Integrated Services

May 2020 - Jan 2021

- Developed cross-platform mobile applications with Google Flutter, incorporating top-notch design principles to meet and exceed customer requirements.
- Contributed to the design, development, and testing of innovative solutions, including backend applications, to enhance user interactions in an Agile scrum environment.
- Integrate third-party APIs and collaborated with backend engineers to define and implement RESTful API services with ASP.NET Core.
- Translated design mockups into functional web applications, utilizing a range of web ap services and integrating SOAP web services.
- Collaborated closely with fellow developers to troubleshoot complex issues, conduct root-cause analyses, and develop effective solutions.
- Supported the organization's testing model, ensuring that backend components and client solutions adhered to requirements and delivered reliability.
- Conducted thorough code reviews, improving code quality and expanding knowledge through peer feedback and programming best practices.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Information Technology – Middlesex University, London
 Relevant Modules: Artificial Intelligence, Web-based Mobile Applications, Novel Interaction
 Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering (ADSE) – Aptech World Wide
 CompTIA A+ Certification – Aptech World Wide
 2019 – 2020
 2019